CHRISTINE SCHATZ

CONTACT

www.christineschatz.com

**** 323-828-8487

♀ New York

in linkedin.com/in/christineschatz

ChristineSchatz

SUMMARY

I truly enjoy problem solving. Whether it's figuring out how an app's data should be structured or how a user experience should be designed, I'm energized by crafting creative solutions to problems. I'm drawn to good people who enjoy sharing ideas and making a difference.

EDUCATION

Northampton Community College

A.S. Computer Science 2015 Dean's List, GPA: 3.9

Dev Bootcamp

Web Development 2015

University of California, San Diego

B.A. Visual Arts: Media 2008 Graduated with Honors

SKILLS

LANGUAGES: Ruby, JavaScript, Java, PHP, Scala

FRAMEWORKS / LIBRARIES: Rails, Laravel

TESTING: RSpec, Capybara

FRONT END: HTML5, CSS3, Sass, jQuery, React,

Riot

METHODOLOGIES: Object-oriented design, Agile **DATABASE:** ActiveRecord, PostgreSQL, SQL

DEVOPS: Docker, Vagrant

ACTIVITIES

The Loop · Founder & Writer

Music blogger for popular, Hype-Machine ranked music blog "The Loop." I work with PR agents and artists to feature independent music. I'm also a music reviewer for Fluence.io

Coders > Cancer Hackathon · Developer

Collaborated on a team of 4 to develop Ladybug, a text messaging system that reminds women to do their monthly self breast exam. Used Ruby on Rails and HTML5, CSS3, and jQuery to design the splash page

EMPLOYMENT

Junior Full Stack Engineer PetFlow

New York, NY Jan 2016 to Current

- Used JavaScript, riot.js, jQuery to implement front end features
- Used PHP (Laravel) on the backend
- Wrote unit tests
- Refactored parts of a large codebase

Junior Developer (Contract) ValuePenguin New York, NY Oct 2015 to Dec 2015

- Built interactive tools such as a financial calculator
- Used JavaScript, React, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, and Sass to build features on the front end
- Wrote Scala and PHP to customize data on the back end
- Developed in Docker containers

Web Editor & Coordinator - Entrepreneurship Program Lafayette College

Easton, PA Jul 2013 to Jun 2015

- Developed the footprints for an entrepreneurship initiative
- Implemented JavaScript, HTML & CSS to departmental website
- Worked with external partners & alumni to curate entrepreneurship-focused events

Project Analyst East Greenville, PA Knoll Jan 2013 to Jun 2013

- Compiled and analyzed data from supply chain work streams
- Created master project plan using project management software

PROJECTS

the <hive>

A social networking site for software developers looking to collaborate on a side project. Users can coordinate meetups using an in-app messaging system. Users can also search for a project by any given city or zip code.

- Played a large role in implementing the Google Geocoding API to render location results.
- Designed the splash page
- Built a portion of the CRUD features for projects
- Implemented AJAX for smoother data loading

Stack: Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Materialize, Sass URL: https://code-hive.herokuapp.com

Emotional Baggage Check iOS app

The iOS app version of the popular desktop site Emotional Baggage Check. Users can post "baggage" anonymously as well as receive an anonymous response.

- Used Swift and Parse API as a backend
- Utilized MVC design pattern, divide and conquer strategies, and debugging tools throughout development

Stack: Swift, Objective-C, Parse

AWARDS

Style of Sound Best Music Blog Award

Awarded ranking in Style of Sound's "Most Influential Music Blogs of 2014" list

Oct 2014